但如果我们...
But if we...
- 但是怎么... - 老天
- But how can? - Jesus Christ.
这就是说
So this means that...
- 但是... - 这么说没有谁杀了什么流浪汉
- But...  - So no one killed any homeless men.
没有什么连环杀手
No serial killer.
有些是随机的凶案
Some were random killings,
有些可能是自然死亡被伪造成谋杀
some were natural deaths that were likely manipulated.
但彼此没有任何联系 为什么?
- But they're not linked in any way. - But why?
警探用利用资金调查一年前
The detectives used the money to fund a case against the drug traffickers responsible
空屋屠杀的主谋毒贩
for the slayings in the vacants a year ago.
直接的结果 就是上周的大规模逮捕行动
Last week's arrests and seizures were a direct result.
我理理头绪...
So let me just understand this.
所以我几周来在外面嚷嚷
So I've been going out there for weeks,
抨击州长忽视流浪汉
slamming the Governor for his neglect of the homeless
声称我们会不惜一切代价抓到
and declaring how we will stop at nothing to find the person responsible
那个残杀流浪汉的凶手 但其实...
for preying on the homeless and all the while...
Norman 这可是我的烂摊子呢
Hey, Norman, this is my ass here.
那是啊 老大
That's true, boss.
但还真是挺好玩的
But it does have a certain charm to it.
他们捏造事件拿钱
They manufactured an issue to get paid,
我们捏造事件让你能选上州长
we manufactured an issue to get you elected governor.
大家靠着捏造的事实各取所需
Everybody's getting what they need behind some make-believe.
涉案的警探会被停职  最后至少会被解雇
The detectives involved will be suspended and ultimately fired, at the least.
除此之外 可能还会有欺诈和伪证的刑事起诉
Beyond that, a criminal prosecution on fraud and perjury charges is probable.
那又怎样 你是说我们开个新闻发布会
You're saying we call a press conference and we say,
跟人说"对了,流浪汉凶杀案的一切"
"By the way, all that stuff about homeless people getting killed
还有"州长削弱了安全网络"
"and the Governor cutting the safety net, and...
还有我们所谓"不惜一切代价抓住凶手"
"us doing everything in our power to catch the guy,
"你们猜怎样 都是我们自作孽" 更不必说
- "guess what, the joke's on us?" - Not to mention that the evidence
上周毒贩逮捕行动证据有问题
against the traffickers arrested last week is tainted.
也可能立不了案
That case could collapse as well.
真他妈不敢相信
I don't fucking believe this.
你俩给我盯紧了
You two are on point here.
这话要是传到安纳波利斯州长会把我往死里整
Word of this gets down to Annapolis, the Governor's gonna wreck me with it.
到那时 你们也得走人 我发誓
And if it comes to that, you guys drop on your swords, so help me.
我们把警探停职外面怎么会没有风言风语
How does word not get out once we suspend the detectives?
更别说到大陪审团那儿提起刑事诉讼了
Never mind sending it to the grand jury for a criminal case?
犯下这事的警探必须走人 你不是想说我还得容忍吧
The cops that did this, they gotta go. You cannot be telling me I have to live with this.
副局长 律师...
Deputy, Counselor...
不好意思 我们首先得把这事
if you two will excuse us, we are going to discuss this first
作为一个行政问题进行讨论
as a matter of public policy.
在我们找出一个最好的解决办法前
Until we can reason the best way to address this,
不要轻举妄动也别跟任何人提起
do nothing and speak to no one about any of this.
如果此事被不适当地公开
If this becomes public in the wrong way,
一大票对此事负有法律责任的人
a lot of people who were legally responsible for the situation,
有监督之职的善良的人...
good people who were, nonetheless, in a supervisory role here...
都没好日子过
are going to suffer.
谁都不想弄到这步田地
And that's not the outcome that anyone wants.
Mike的意思是我们必须谨慎处理
What Mike is saying is that we need to be very careful about how to proceed.
真希望我还在报社 那我就可以写这新闻了
I wish I was still at the newspaper so I could write on this mess.
太他妈精彩了
It's too fucking good.
* When you walk through the garden *
火线重案组 第五季 第10集 全剧大结局
the.wire.s05e10
* You gotta watch your back *
* Well I beg your pardon *
* Walk the straight and narrow track *
* If you walk with Jesus *
* He's gonna save your soul *
* You gotta keep the devil *
* Way down in the hole *
* He's got the fire and the fury *
* At his command *
* Well you don't have to worry *
* If you hold on to Jesus hand *
* We'll all be safe from Satan *
* When the thunder rolls *
* Just gotta help me keep the devil *
* Way down in the hole *
" ...国王的生活"  H. L. Mencklen
- Lester - 什么风把你吹到这儿来了
Lester. What brings you down?
今天好像没有你的预约啊
We don't have anything scheduled from you today, I don't think...
在木板路的Showboat酒店输了4万
40,000 from the Showboat on the boardwalk.
在Borgata输了2万6千
26 at the Borgata.
去年在泰姬陵酒店输了8万...
80 over the last year at the Taj Mahal
这还只是在大西洋城的赌场里输的
and that's just the Atlantic City casinos.
我喜欢赌博 那又怎样
I like to play. So what?
你过去两年输了三倍于你薪水的金额
You lost three times your salary over the last two years.
我在Sentinel Title查了你 找到7页的抵押合同(经营产权保险和抵押)
I ran you through Sentinel Title and came back with seven pages of liens
和一份你两个月前办的第三顺位抵押
and a third mortgage you folded on two months ago.
Gary 你完了
Gary, you're done.
什么意思
What do you mean?
我们在毒贩的屋里找到了 密封的大陪审团文件
We found sealed grand jury papers in the houses of drug dealers
也有人作证是从你这儿来的
and we've got people naming you on it.
你有麻烦了 Gary
You have a problem, Gary.
但你在法院里有朋友 终身不渝的朋友
But you have friends in this courthouse, lifelong friends.
直面问题吧 把收买你的人供出来
Cop to the problem, give up the names of those that bought from you.
取消律师资格? 肯定的
Disbarred? Yeah, no doubt.
但你从此清白了
But you play it clean from this moment on
我们都心知肚明 你很可能逃脱惩罚
and we both know you'll probably walk.
你为什么会盯上我 我查了过去两年
- Why did you look at me? - I ran the finances
每个在这单位工作的人财政状况
on everyone who worked this unit over the last couple years.
只有你有问题 如果地检不是一团乱麻
You were the only bogie. If the S.A.O. Weren't so screwed up,
本该循例做这种背景调查的
they'd have been running background checks as a routine.
不过我猜你也知道
But I guess you knew that.
我总琢磨着他们究竟能不能查出来
I always wondered if they'd get their shit together.
不过这就是巴尔的摩 不是么
But that's Baltimore, isn't it?
现在怎么办
So what happens now?
首先...
Well, for starters...
打个电话
you're gonna make a phone call.
McNulty  Freamon  Sydnor
McNulty, Freamon, Sydnor...
掺和这事的都得走人
Any one who has the smell of this on them should be gone.
在工作完成前 他们就得停职
Before the close of business, they should be suspended
这周之内提起诉讼
and, before the end of the week, indicted.
- 我知道 但... - 但什么
- I know, but... - But what?
传出去会有损Carcetti的利益 所以我们就听之任之?
We're gonna let this shit stand because it'll hurt Carcetti to air it out?
他不是像我们一样要清理门户  而是想着怎么藏污纳垢
Instead of cleaning house like we need to, he's up there figuring out how to hide the dirt.
我发誓 我会亲自给州长打电话 任这事传出去
I got a mind to call the Governor myself and just let it fly.
- Cedric 不能这样 - 为什么
- Cedric, you can't. - Why not?
如果我不作出处理以后面对知道这事的警探
If I let this thing stand, I might as well just roll over and play deaf
就都得睁一只眼闭一只眼
for every police who knows about this.
- 我们隐瞒这事... - Cedric 你不能做什么
- We cover this up... - Cedric, you can't do anything.
那些是你的手下
Those are your detectives.
他们要找人背黑锅 就会找你...
They need someone to blame, they will measure you for it.
我他妈不在乎
I don't give a fuck.
他们还会炒了我
And they'll fire me.
你听到Steintorf的话了...
You heard Steintorf.
这案子是我负责的
I was in charge of this thing.
窃听是我争取来的...
I was on that wiretap.
这事关我的职业生涯 我的一切
This is my career. This is everything.
你公开这事损害了Carcetti
You go public and it hurts Carcetti.
也许他当不了州长  但他还是市长
Maybe he doesn't get to be governor but he is still the Mayor,
Bond也还是我上司
and Bond is still my boss,
你知道最终倒霉的不会是他们
and you know the weight will not fall on them.
- 从来不会 - 老天
- It never does. - Christ.
这么多年来 我在法院里一直埋头苦干
Everything I worked for, all those years in that courthouse...
求你了
Please.
25美分 "巴尔的摩太阳报"
25 cents. Baltimore Sun.
- 先生 "巴尔的摩太阳报" 25美分 - 来一份
Sir, Baltimore Sun. One quarter.
- 别找了 - 谢谢 先生 谢谢
- Keep it. - Thank you, sir. Thank you.
小费都给得不少嘛
People tip pretty good, don't they?
他的所作所为让我们痛心
"...paying him for what he had done to us.
我为他感到遗憾 真的
"I'm sorry for him, man, really,
但我还是不能让他离开地下室住上来
"but I still can't let him come up from the basement."
你要登到报纸上吗  我是这么想的
- You gonna put all that in the paper? - That's the plan.
Sherrod那部分也要吗
Even the parts about Sherrod?
嗯
Yeah.
这故事... 这故事有什么好登的  -什么故事
- What good is a story like that? - Like what?
我 Sherrod 嗑药 不嗑药
Like me, Sherrod. Gettin' high. Not gettin' high.
我妹妹 纸上写那些
My sister, all that shit in there.
登上报纸有什么用
What good do any of that do to put it in the newspaper?
读者会看到 会思考 也许会有不一样的感触
People read it, they think about it. Maybe see things different.
我可不觉得 伙计
I don't know, man.
Bubs 你不让我登 我就不登
Bubs, you don't want me to do this, I won't do it.
我不知道
I don't know.
"巴尔的摩太阳报" 来点阳光吧 太阳报
Baltimore Sun. A little bit of sun. Sun paper.
听着 Rupert 你想的话可以公开此事
Look, Rupert, go public with this thing if you want
但你的部门首当其冲 一开始是你们让此事发生
but your shop is gonna come out looking worse for letting it happen in the first place.
最好是把这事压下来
The better move is to shut it down quietly
再暗中处理责任人
and then deal with those responsible through back channels.
我们安静地把他们整治了 这么深的坑
We'll bury these guys softly and in a hole so deep
没人会想着挖出来
no one will ever get close to digging them up.
我懂
I can see that.
局长 你同意吗
Commissioner, do you agree?
对我来说有点麻烦
Well, it is a little more problematic for me.
责任人在我的部门里 不是吗
The offenders are in my shop, are they not?
我私下跟你聊两句行吗 Bill?
Can I have a word with you in private, Bill?
如果Rawls不干 我也不干
Hey, if Rawls isn't in, I'm not either.
我不担心Bill Rawls
I wouldn't worry about Bill Rawls.
我看 他现在可等到了人生重大转折呢....
I believe he's about to have one of those road to Damascus moments.
我知道你在想什么
I can see what you're thinking in there.
我知道你的如意算盘
I can see the gears grinding in that head of yours.
你在想 嘿 我可以给Carcetti设些障碍
You're thinking, "Hey, I might have some wood on Carcetti here.
毕竟这事他们如果不整治小弟Daniels
"There's no way they can pin the blame on me for this fiasco
就更怪不到我头上了 你想着我们要炒你 就得先炒掉Daniels
"without doing their boy Daniels, too." You're thinking we'd have to fire Daniels
而鉴于我们那么卖力地推销Daniels 再炒掉他就太不值了
to fire you and that wouldn't sit well, given how much we've already sold Daniels.
你是不是这样想的
Isn't that what you're thinking?
所以你想浑水摸鱼
You're telling yourself maybe there's a way for you to leverage this,
让自己当满一届任期的局长
to get yourself a full term as commissioner,
让Daniels迟几年上台 作为交换你管好自己的嘴
to delay Daniels a few more years in exchange for you shutting the fuck up
照我们说的做
and doing what you're told.
你知道吗 Bill? 你也不是太异想天开
And you know what, Bill? You're not far off.
你是可以浑水摸鱼 不过就摸那么一两条
You do have a little leverage here but just a little.
我不会坏了你的好事
I wouldn't overplay your hand.
那你想怎么玩
How would you play it?
我会闭上嘴等你行动
I'd shut the fuck up and wait your turn
等Tommy当了州长 他就让你
and, when Tommy gets to the statehouse, he brings you with him
跟着他做州局长
to be State Police Superintendent.
因为你当巴尔的摩的局长
Because while you may be a shade too white
毕竟白了点
to run the Baltimore department,
当州局长就刚刚好了
you're just about right for the M.S.P.
- 说好了? - 说好了
- I have your word? - And I have yours.
就后台操作吧
Back channel is the way to go.
看吧 警察局长想通了
See? The Police Commissioner done fell off his ass.
有什么事吗
Can I help you?
我想见Prezbo先生
I need to see Mr. Prezbo.
会有人下来
Someone will come down.
- 你是这儿的学生吗 - Donnelly女士 是我 Duquan
- Are you a student here? - Ms. Donnelly, it's me, Duquan.
很高兴见到你 Duquan 但你不是这儿的学生了
It's good to see you but you're not a student here
我不能让你进去
so I can't let you inside.
我只是顺道来看看Prezbo先生
I just came past to see Mr. Prezbo.
他现在在上课呢
Well, he's teaching right now.
我知道 我等着就好
I know. I can wait.
那你得待在外面
You're gonna have to stay outside.
打下课铃后 我会告诉Pryzbylewski先生你等着见他 行吗
After the bell, I'll tell Mr. Pryzbylewski you're out here for him, OK?
我要给你个惊喜
I'm going to surprise you with something.
你已经给过了
You already have.
我从线人那儿 获得了大陪审团泄密的情报
I got a tip from an informant about a leak out of the grand jury unit.
不幸的是已经确认了
Sad to say it's checked out.
- 我们知道有人泄密 - 对 但你知道是谁吗
- We know about the leak. - But do you know who it is?
Gary Dipasquale
Gary diPasquale.
正派人啊 就是好赌
Decent enough guy but he's got a bear of a gambling problem
况且还有一票毒贩律师排着队给他送钱
and a bank of drug lawyers who are willing to pay for their look-sees.
Troy Sanders Marvin Bronfman
Troy Sanders, Marvin Bronfman,
Dennis Cray Sid Silverstein
Dennis Cray, Sid Silverstein.
名单上最重要的一个 Maurice Levy
And the pick of the litter? Maurice Levy.
不骗你
I kid you not.
- Gary泄的密? - 他当场就招了
Gary is their leak?
准备好坦白了 他想这样
He broke right away. He was ready to give it up. Needed to.
一方同意录音的电话 表明Maury Levy有牵连
One-party consent call implicating Maury Levy.
-Gary人呢 -他去了二楼
- Where's Gary now? - He went up to the second floor
提交辞职信 接着回家等待处罚
to hand in his letter of resignation and went home to wait for the sword to drop.
他没事 比你想的要好
He's OK, he's better than you'd think.
知道吗 如果我们能让Levy招供 还有其他的毒贩律师
You know, if we can turn Levy and some of these other drug lawyers,
我们就能查明全城的涉毒资金流向
we can route the drug money all over town.
这是个可悲的工作 我知道
It's sad business, I know,
但至少现在我们知道真相了 对吧
but at least we know the truth now, right?
你说真相?
The truth, you say?
- 嗨 - 你好 Duquan
Duquan, hello.
- 当心咯 - 嘿
Snatch-pops.
Damien 你疯了吗
Damien. You lost your mind?
- 但我说了当心了 - 我不管你说了什么
- But I said snatch-pops. - I don't care.
你得买个三明治给他
You're gonna buy him a new sandwich,
然后你要进去向Williams先生
and past that, you're gonna ask Mr. Williams for a broom
借个扫帚把这里清理干净 懂吗
to clean that up, you understand?
- 但P先生... - 马上 Damien 否则我就再罚你放学后留堂一周
Right now or you're mine for another week of detention.
我不想再听到你辩解什么了
I don't want to hear another word.
看样子你掌握到窍门了
It looks like you got the hang of it.
你最近怎么样 Duquan?
What's up with you?
老样子
Ain't nothing.
你还在西南区?
You still at Southwestern?
我需要休学一学期
Well, I'm, like, needing a semester off, you know?
我现在无家可归
I'm outdoors now.
还有...
And...
我想也许我能找你
I was hoping maybe I could get with you
借些钱我就能找个地方 买些干净的衣服
and borrow some money, so I can get a place and some clean clothes
让自己安顿下来 这样我就能回学校了
and get myself settled so I can go back to school.
你现在流浪街头?
You're on the street?
有人愿意提供我一个很不错的地方
I got people ready to give me a really good place
如果我能付些钱的话
if I can come up with some money for it.
要多少
How much do you need?
两百块吧
Couple of hundred.
如果你能多给我50
But if you could go one fifty more,
我就能报名巴尔的摩社区大学的一般教育发展考试
I can enrol in the G.E.D. Program down B.C.C.C.,
那我不用回西南区就能 参加一般教育发展考试了
then I could get my G.E.D. Without having to go back to Southwestern.
然后我就能获得工作许可
Then I can get my work permit.
我想你还在上高中的年纪
I don't think you're eligible for a G.E.D. Program
不符合参加考试的条件 Duquan
if you're still of age to attend high school.
可以的
Yeah, you are.
这样吧
I'll tell you what.
等我几分钟 我载你过去
Give me a couple minutes, I'll drive you down there.
如果你可以参加考试 我就开张支票当场给那儿的会计
If you are eligible, I'll write a check right to the bursar's office.
不用了 P先生 你没必要事事亲为
No, Mr. P., you ain't got to go through all that.
再说我今天也没空过去
Besides, I ain't got the time to go down there today.
但你知道 我一定会去的
But, you know, I'm gonna.
我可以给你 Duquan 如果你想的话
I can do it, if that's what you want.
钱我不在乎
And I don't even care about the money.
不过你要知道我过几天会去社区大学看看
But understand I'm gonna go down to B.C.C.C. In a few days
看你有没有报名
and find out if you're enrolled.
如果你报名了 我得说
And if you are, I'm gonna say, "Great.
"太好了 Duquan通过了就能拿到执照"
"Duquan can come past with his certificate when he gets it,
"我们还是朋友
"and we're still friends.
他还可以依靠我"
"And he can still rely on me."
但如果你没报名...
But if you aren't enrolled, then...
我想我就再也见不到你了 对吧
Well, I imagine I'm not gonna see you again, am I?
不会的 P先生
No, Mr. P.
我绝对会报名的
I'm definitely gonna enroll.
走着瞧吧
You'll see.
我去取东西 停车场见
I'll get my stuff. I'll meet you in the lot
我们去找个取款机
and we'll go find a bank machine.
Jay 我要说的就是该查的我们都查了
Jay, all I'm saying is we've run down all the leads we had,
报告都在这了 这个时候
all the office reports are in and, at this point,
除非有新的发展  我不需要这些个人力资源了
barring any new developments, I don't need all this fucking manpower.
操 Jimmy  上周你还哭爹喊娘
Fuck me, Jimmy. Last week you were crying
要找所有你能找到的人力
for every swinging dick you could get your hands on.
案子沉寂了 没有红丝带 没有尸体
The case has gone quiet. There's no red ribbons,
没有失踪了 电话他妈的也不响了
no bodies, no disappearances.Not a fucking word on the cellphone.
这些玩意都没用了
This thing's useless.
怎么 你现在连监听也不用了?
You don't want the wiretap either, now?
法官给了我们60天 等到期了 那就...
The judge gave us 60 days. Once that runs out, then...
混账 相信有连环杀手的人就是你
Motherfucker, you were the one who was all semper fi for this serial killer
你他妈现在又不认了
and now you're fuckin' the dog.
Jay 我已经在办这个案子了
I'm ready to work the case.
但没有新线索和进展 你还想让我怎么办
But short of any new leads, what the fuck do you want me to do?
总不能编吧
I can't make shit up, can I?
该怎样就是怎样
It is what it is.
如果我把监视小队打发走 Jimmy
If I send the surveillance teams back,
明天别来哭着跟我要人 听见了吗
don't come crying for more manpower tomorrow, you hear?
就像一场战争 不是吗
Shit is like a war, ain't it?
进去容易 出来就难了
Easy to get in, hell to get out.
Pearlman都知道了 Daniels也是 他们察觉出来了
Pearlman knows everything. Daniels, too. They figured it out.
- 怎么会啊 - 不知道
- How? - I don't know.
老天 他们...-不知道
- Jesus. What are they? - I don't know.
她说得明明白白不能再有流浪汉谋杀
She made it clear there are not to be any further homeless killings.
这案子不能再有任何动静
Nothing more on this case whatsoever.
她是否知道Marlo 我们的案子...-她什么都知道 Daniels也知道
- Does she know about Marlo, that our case? - She knows everything. Daniels knows.
他们去了证物管理科 拨了监听的电话号码
They went to the E.C.U., dialed up the wiretap number
Marlo的手机响了
and up pops Marlo's cellphone.
那我们怎么还没被炒  为什么还没戴上手铐
Why aren't we fired? Why aren't we in fucking bracelets?
不知道
I don't know.
靠 Lester
Oh shit, Lester.
我们得脱身 把事情理顺
We gotta get outta here. We gotta think this thing through.
老天
Jesus fucking Christ.
十分钟后在Kavanaugh酒吧见 行吗
Look, meet me down at Kavanagh's in ten minutes, all right?
Jimmy?
多少
How much?
- 200 - 靠 伙计
200.Damn, boy.
老师肯定很喜欢你 走吧
Teacher must love your black ass.C'mon with it.
他们会把测试器放在白桦林里
They gonna put out testers up on Poplar Grove.
我们要迟到了
We gonna be late for it.
驾 孩子 驾
C'mon, boy.
副局长...
Deputy.
没完
To be continued.
- 操 操 操 操 - 怎么了
- Fuck, fuck, fucking fuck. - What's the matter?
午餐又是农家奶酪 Carl?
Cottage cheese for lunch again there, Carl?
发生了不代表是新闻
Just because it happened doesn't mean it's news.
总有某个地方会爆发沙门氏菌
There's always a salmonella outbreak somewhere.
我看不出有什么必要报道这个...
I don't see why we have to cover this one...
改稿的首要原则是什么 Spry?
What's the first rule of rewrite, Spry?
推倒重来
Shoot it down.
你看了吗
Did you read this?
我们要把报道
We are crediting our own coverage
寄希望于州长改变主意吗?
with changing the Governor's mind?
我已经读到结语了
I'm already to the jump
还没看到任何人
and there's not a quote from anyone
对此作出的确切的说法
crediting us with anything of the sort.
嗯 州长是要恢复专款了
The guv is restoring funding, all right.
因为Carcetti在这个问题上 狠咬了他一口
That's 'cause Carcetti's been beating the shit out of him on this issue.
我们只是事后诸葛亮
We're just an afterthought.
Whiting快拿下公共服务普利策奖了吧
Whiting can smell the public service Pulitzer?
-大概吧 -你看了吗
- Seems so. - You get a chance yet?
嗯 嗯 看了
Yeah, yeah. I read it.
怎么样
And?
很不错
Beautiful.
不 不 我说真的
No, no, no. I mean it.
你把人物刻画得很深刻
You got some real Joe Mitchell stuff on the page there.
让我觉得自己了解这个人和他的世界
Really makes me feel like I know this guy and his world.
你成功地管窥全豹
You just pulled it all through the keyhole.
谢谢夸奖 Gus
Thanks, Gus.
好文章啊 我会放到周日的头版
We get some good art, I'm gonna push for the Sunday front.
其实呢 我还得征得他本人同意
Well, I gotta make sure the guy is good with it.
什么意思
What do you mean?
关于那孩子的那部分还是让他很困扰
The part of the story about the kid bothers him.
当他跟我谈起的时候  只是说个不停...
When he told me about it, he was just talking...
你告诉过他你会写他的故事了吧
You told him you were writing about him?
我知道 但...我们是把人家的人生公之于众
I know, but... I'm putting the guy's life out there.
我只想一切明明白白的 你知道我什么意思吧
I wanna feel clean about it. You know what I'm sayin'?
我就记得明明白白了
I remember clean.
我们还没锒铛入狱 显然他们不急于公之于众
Obviously, they're not in a hurry to go public 'cause we ain't cuffed.
他们向我们一样继续假装查案 为什么?
They're pretending on this case like we're pretending. Why?
Carcetti 他会被推上风口浪尖
Carcetti. He's exposed on this.
怎么会  把责任推到我们和警局头上就好
How? Just blame it all on us, on the department.
干掉我们  他们就得干掉Rawls Daniels
To kill us, they'd have to kill Rawls, Daniels
和半数的指挥系统 他提拔了他们
and half the chain of command. And he made those guys.
这是他的警局
It's his police department.
要传出去他就是在竞选州长的时候 自毁长城
So he opens himself up right when he's out there, running for governor.
那他们想让我们怎么做 悄悄地把这个案子整没了?我没意见啊
So they want us to do what? Run it down quietly? That's no problem.
六个月内 竞选后
Six months from now, after the election,
他们可能会公开 并把我们送审
they might decide to open up and grand jury us.
我们还是可能进监狱 就算不会
We could still go to jail and, if not,
我估计也得被扔会证管科了 而你 伙计 又得开你的船去了
I expect to be back in the pawn shop unit and you are gonna ride the boat.
那又怎样 那也值了
So what? It was worth it.
是吗
Wasn't it?
看情况了
Depends.
在知道了真相后 他们还愿不愿给
Are they gonna let the case against Marlo and his people stand,
Marlo 和他手下的案子立案
knowing what they know?
为什么不呢 逮捕和电话窃听依然有效
Why wouldn't they? It still works on the seizures and cellphones.
咱也没有非法窃听 是啊
- It works without the illegal tap. - Yeah, it does.
再说抓住Marlo 他们也大张旗鼓了一番
And they made a big deal about dropping Marlo.
召开了新闻发布会说他是空屋谋杀案的主谋
They called that press conference and linked him to all the bodies.
现在放弃这案子...
For them to drop the case now...
你想想...
You know, you think about it,
我们是互相拽着小辫子
we've got almost as much on them as they do on us.
那个想自己成Tom Wolfe（著名记者）的家伙
That Tom Wolfe wannabe
觉得这句话我能给他通过吗
thinks he's gonna get a phrase like that past me?
去他的 混球
No fuckin' way, motherfucker.
好比一件露出线头的毛衣
It's like a sweater with the threads hanging off.
随便扯一根线头...
Pull any thread...
多数是夸张和太过完美的引用
Mostly exaggerations and too-perfect quotes,
有些是公开宣布的
sometimes on the record.
我给其中一些人打了电话
I called some of them back,
问他们是不是真说过那些话
asked if they really said those things.
你知道房管局局长
You know what the city housing commissioner told me
- 对报道里提到的话是怎么说的吗 - 嗯?
about the quotes in the flipping story?
他希望是他说的 但他这辈子就没这么聪明过
He wished he'd said some of them but that he'd never been that smart in his life.
要是有人花点时间...
Someone takes the time to...
重新报道 事情就大条了
re-report this stuff, it'll get ugly.
你准备怎么办
What're you gonna do?
不知道 Robert 我不知道
I don't know, Robert. I don't know.
别把我扯进去
Keep my name out of it.
不准保释
No bail.
他们在保释审查里 宣称你有暴力倾向 恐吓证人
They're claiming a propensity for violence and witness intimidation at the bail review,
把你作为主要嫌疑人扣着
trying to have you held as the kingpin.
-他们可以这么做吗 -可以尝试
- They can do that? - They can try.
看他们抽到哪个法官了
Depends on which judge they draw.
那Chris也不准保释咯?他背着谋杀逮捕令呢
So they ain't got no bail for Chris, right? I mean, he got the murder one.
还有Monk
Monk neither.
他车里货太多了 又在04年指控的假释期
Too much weight in his car and he's on parole from the '04 charge.
我能做的只有用30万保释Wagstaff先生
Best I could do was spring Mr. Wagstaff on 300,000.
-他有那么多钱吗 -他叔叔的房子
- He show that kind of money? - Put up his uncle's house
抵价三分之一的保释金 担保人用一份假的留置权抵偿其余的部分
on surety bond for a third of it. Bondsman is fronting the rest on a fake lien.
现在重点不是保释 重要的是...
Right now, the important thing is not bail, the important thing is this...
你得告诉我还有谁知道你的钟点密码
I need you to tell me who else knew your clock code.
我说过了
I told you.
我 Cheese Monk Chris
Me, Cheese, Monk, Chris
还有供货的 就这些了
- and the supply. That's it.
-没别人了? -除了你 其他人甚至连我手机号都没有
- No one else? -No one else even had my cell number, except you.
干嘛
What?
-某处有人撒谎 -我没骗你
- There's a lie in here somewhere. - I ain't lying.
不是说你
I don't mean you.
你看 警察说那天
Look, the police say the source told them
有线人报告你们在补货
that you were re-upping on the day
这类消息是会传出去的 这有可能
and word of that might have slipped out. That's possible.
我是说 毕竟你是给整个城市做批发...
If you were wholesaling all over town...
但他们逮捕你时只搜走了你的手机 接着他们需要法庭授权
They only grab your cells when they arrest you and then they have to go get warrants
才能查看你手机上的图片
before they can look at the photos on the phones.
只有他们拿到了图片
And it's only when they get to the photos
破译了密码
and break the code that they have enough
才能起诉你和Chris 对吧
to type a charging document for you or Chris, right?
我的意思是 你被捕时并没有携带毒品
I mean, you aren't caught with drugs.
但他们在几小时内 就拿来了你和Chris的逮捕令
But they had the arrest warrants on both of you within a couple hours.
也就是说他们几乎是立刻破解了密码
Which means that they broke the code almost instantly,
一秒都不耽误
no time at all.
他们窃听我
They wiretapped me.
我的调查员是这么想的
My investigator thinks so.
但他说他不清楚是哪个单位干的 谁牌的人
But he doesn't know for sure which unit ran the tap or who manned it.
不对劲
It doesn't add up.
你可以出去了
You gettin' out.
你没戏
You ain't.
到街头去 尽可能调集人手 抓住那小子
You hit the streets, you round up as much muscle as possible and get that boy.
他知道我要对付他 所以他杀了Snoop
He did Snoop 'cause he knew we was on him.
他知道我要找他麻烦 因为补货的事是他泄露出去的
He knew we was on him 'cause he the one talked about the re-up.
都收拾好
Get your shit together, man.
担保人会跟Levy一块儿过来
The bondsman came in with Levy.
行 我就去准备
A'ight. I'm on it.
伙计 有一块钱吗
Man, you got a dollar?
给点吧
C'mon.
嘿 伙计
Pal.
嘿
Hey.
你还好吧
Pal, you all right?
它来了...
OK, here it comes,
死亡之蟹爪
the dreaded crab claw.
你们知道蟹爪出现意味着什么...
You know what happens when crab claw goes...
- 糟糕了... - 不许用蟹爪!
- It's all crab tonight... - No crab claw!
就要 蟹爪!
Yes, crab claw!
蟹爪又做到了 6个!
Yeah! Crab claw does it again. Six!
6个 我不玩了...
Six and I'm out...
喂?
Yeah.
在哪
Where?
开玩笑吧
You're fucking kidding me.
更扯淡了...
It's more bull...
我告诉你 Jay 那是假的...
It's bogus, Jay. I'm telling you...
好吧
OK.
我得走了
I gotta go.
做戏得做全套 没办法
I have to keep running the string out. I've no choice.
你说上面的人都知道了
You said the bosses know.
有些知道 有些不知道 知道的那些也要我们装下去
Some do, some don't. The ones that do want us to keep pretending.
我们不装了 那就...
We stop pretending, then...
我们明晚再玩好吗
Listen, we'll finish this tomorrow night, OK?
回见
I'll see you in a bit.
你怎么想
What do you think?
让我那些破事成为街谈巷议
I mean, puttin' my shit in the streets?
是你嘛
Well, it's you.
他抓得很准
He's got you.
这个嘛...
Yeah, well.
我是说他把你看得很透
I mean he's got what you're about.
他喜欢你 字里行间就能看出来
The guy likes you, that shows through.
你看 他说你的现在的回馈社会
I mean, you know, he's saying this giving back that you're doing,
是因为Sherrod
he's putting that up against Sherrod.
他不能让你摆脱困境...
He ain't lettin' you off the hook for shit
只是把一切如实登出来
but he's just puttin' it all out there.
好的 坏的
You know, the good and the bad.
知道吗
You know what?
坏的传出去也没什么
The bad don't bother me to have out there.
那些龌龊事我不会瞒着谁
Shit, I know the bad. I ain't lyin' to no one about the bad.
怕别人说你是个好人?
Scared of somebody callin' you good?
很多人在社区里做志愿者 很多人在互助会上分享自己的经历
A lot of folks volunteer places. A lot of folks share at meetings.
早起没嗑药的人多得是
Plenty of motherfuckers wake up every day and not get high.
他让我看起来很特殊 但我只是做我该做的事
Man makin' me sound special for doin' what the fuck I need to be doin'.
读读吧 臭小子
Read it.
"你可以逃避这世上的痛苦"
"You can hold back from the suffering of the world,
"这是你的自由"
"you have free permission to do so
"也与你的天性相符"
"and it is in accordance with your nature.
"但或许你唯一能逃避的"
"But perhaps this very holding back
"只是这逃避本身"
"is the one suffering you could have avoided."
弗兰兹 卡夫卡
Fran-zee Kafka.
谁啊
Who's he?
某个作家
Some writer.
你读过他的书?
You read his books?
操 没有 你记得Flubber吗
Fuck no. But you remember Flubber?
他让我领导圣马丁互助会那晚
He handed that to me the night that he had me start leading
他递给我的
the Saint Martin meeting.
从那以后我就一直带着
I kept it ever since.
对你有什么意义
What it mean to you?
你还要吗
You want these?
嗯 他说他要收回去 也别复制
Yeah, my man say he need it back and not to make any copies.
他说这个刊登前本来不该给我看的
He say he ain't supposed to show it to me before it goes in the paper.
我是说 如果我让他登的话
I mean, if I let him.
你让他登吗
You gonna?
谢谢你的螃蟹了
Thanks for the crabs.
灰色货车?
Gray van.
-看得见标志吗 -那个距离我看不见
- You get the tag? - I couldn't see it from where I was.
描述一下驾驶者
Describe the driver.
白人 6尺
White. Six foot.
不胖不瘦
Not heavy, not skinny either.
穿着呢
Clothes?
没注意 说不上来
Nothing I noticed. Kinda nondescript.
说不上来?
Nondescript?
我想当时有点吓到了 我就想 哇哦 他干嘛呢
I was surprised, I guess. I just thought, "Whoa, what's he doing?"
-真有趣 居然是你目击到事发 -诡异
- Funny it being you to see this. - It's weird.
要不是有个采访耽误了时间我今晚就不会在这了
If an interview doesn't run late, I'm not even here tonight.
我能进去了吗 我要去报到
You mind if I get inside? I gotta check in with my desk.
还有什么问题可以打我电话
You need anything else, you got my number.
行
Yeah.
那家伙是个混球
That guy's an asshole.
这个瘾君子什么都想不起来了
This smokehound can't remember a thing.
他唯一记得的瞎摆弄他的混球
Only motherfucker he remembers messing with him
就是发现他的人
is the fella that found him.
之前发生了什么天知道
Whatever happened before that is anyone's guess.
嘿
Hey.
有人要绑架你?把你拉进货车里?
Someone try to kidnap you, drag you into a van?
-好吧 - 有人想伤害你吗
- OK. - Who was trying to hurt you?
-我爸 但他喝醉了
My father. But he was a drunk.
警探 这边有个流浪汉  他说他看见了什么
Detective, there's a vagrant over here says he saw something.
你看见了什么 伙计
What did you see, fella?
McNulty?
-Johnny Weaver 机动队的 -靠 你干嘛不早说
- Johnny Weaver. Tactical. - Fuck you. Why didn't you say so?
JW 要掩饰身份吧?
J.W. Tryin' to keep your cover?
还是让这儿的人认为 我是常驻的比较好不是吗
It's better if everyone here thinks I'm one of the regulars.
Petey惹上什么事了
Anyway, what's the ruckus with Petey?
- 那个醉汉? - 对
- The drunk? - Yeah.
太阳报的记者说他正要上楼
Sun reporter says he's going into his building,
看见一个人要把他拽进灰色货车里
he sees a guy trying to drag him into a gray van.
-胡扯吧 -嗯 那混蛋停车之前
- It's bullshit, right? - Yeah. Petey was laying there 45 minutes
Petey已经在这儿躺了45分钟了
before that preppy cocksucker even parks his car.
- 谢谢 - 不客气
- Thanks. - No problem.
给我一块钱 别让人起疑了
Gimme a dollar, make it look right.
谢了 Johnny
Thank you, Jimmy.
那记者怎么办 可以起诉他伪证罪的
What about the reporter? You could charge false statement, you know.
每个骗子你都抓的话拘留所里就关不了其他人了
You lock up every liar, there's no room in B.D.C. For anyone else, right?
得不偿失
More trouble than it's worth.
Jay 假的 我回家了
Jay, it's horseshit. I'm going home.
嗯
Yeah.
我带了些螃蟹
Brought home some crabs.
我已经做了晚餐了
I already made dinner.
放冰箱里吧 你愿意的话明天当午餐吧
Put 'em in the fridge. Cold for lunch tomorrow, if you like.
我吃不完
I can't eat 'em all.
我们不能登这个 尤其不能上头版
We don't run this shit, especially not off the front.
-我亲眼看见的 -Alma跟警方新闻发言人谈过了
- I saw what I saw. - Alma is on the phone with police P. I.O.
无论是正式的和私下的
And they are telling us on the record and off
他们不信任何疑似绑架的报案
that they are discounting any report of a possible abduction.
那有可能 可能是他们没有尽职- 那也不意味着我们不能...
That doesn't mean they're doing their job, and it doesn't mean we...
我们的职责是报道新闻而不是捏造新闻
Our job is to report the news, not to manufacture it.
去你的 Gus
Fuck you, Gus.
好极了
Nice.
我知道他们都嫉妒他的报道取得的成功 - 但事实是...
I know they're jealous of how much play his stories get but the truth is...
- 我们不能报道这事
We cannot run this shit.
你是暗示这都是Scott编的?
Are you suggesting that Scott made any of this up?
你看那些作出这种事的人...
You ever notice that the guys who do that,
Blairs Glass Kelley之流
the Blairs, the Glasses, the Kelleys,
一开始都是些小事
they always start with something small,
先是一两句编造的引言 接着 是整个故事
just a little quote that they clean up. And then it's a whole anecdote,
很快 他们就见证奇迹了
and, pretty soon, they're seeing some amazing shit.
他们会很幸运的碰巧 在特拉维夫站对了地方
They're the lucky ones who just happen to be standing
披萨连锁店正好爆炸了
on the right street corner in Tel Aviv when the pizza joint blows up
人头滚落到街上 眼睛还眨呀眨的
and the human head rolls down the street with the eyes still blinking.
- 是有人给他发的照片 - 但警方已经确认...
The pictures were sent to him. The police have confirmed...
-开始总是一切真实的
It always starts with something true,
可确认的东西
something confirmed.
但接着就会有个狗娘养的
But then you've got a son of a bitch
在神秘的灰色货车来到时
who just happens to be walking in the Guilford entrance
- 刚好经过Guilford入口 - Gus
when the mysterious gray van comes...
你和Scott开始互相针对了
Gus, this has gotten personal between you and Scott
这影响了你的判断
and it's affecting your judgment.
我要把这条新闻移交给州新闻编辑
I'm moving the story through the state desk.
你回家吧 想想清楚
You should go home, think this through.
我们明早再谈
We'll talk in the morning.
也许你会靠这事拿个普利策奖
Maybe you win a Pulitzer with this stuff
也许你拿了还要把奖还回去
and maybe you gotta give it back.
都在我本子上 Gus 发生的一切
It's in my notes, Gus. Everything that happened,
我面对他时他说的每一句话
everything that guy said when I got to him.
每一句都在我本子上
Every last word is in my notes.
比我想的要早回家嘛
Home earlier than I thought.
嗯 回来了
Yeah. Home.
- 他又杀人了 - 谁
- He hit again. - Who did?
连环杀手
The serial killer.
滚你的吧 混蛋
Get a grip, motherfucker.
你不信 自己瞧瞧他左手腕吧
You don't believe me? Check out his left wrist.
又耍我 Bunk?
You fuckin' with me again, Bunk?
模仿犯
Copycat.
给McNulty打电话 叫他过来
Call McNulty. Get him down here.
Ronnie
Maury
我看了Partlow-Stanfield的贩毒罪诉状
Been going over the charging documents on the Partlow-Stanfield drug arrests.
-少说也有些问题 -是吗
- Problematic to say the least. - How so?
他们搜出手机 几分钟后
They grab the phones and, minutes later,
他们就破解了精心设计的 涉及整个组织的密码
they've cracked an elaborate code that implicates everyone.
没人这么聪明
No one's that brilliant,
至少巴尔的摩警局没这种牛人
not at the B.P.D., anyway.
你不认识Lester Freamon
You don't know Lester Freamon.
我知道的
I know what I know.
这让我感觉到你们非法窃听
And this feels to me like an illegal wiretap.
你们守着电话 追踪着他们
Your guys were on those phones, tracking my clients
-早在我委托人还没靠近毒品前就 -非也
- long before they went near any drugs. - Untrue.
等到了证据开释阶段
We get into discovery and I'm going to have no problem
我要击破线人情报的狗屁毫无难度
knocking down that bullshit about a source of information.
而我这里的情报来源告诉我 在预算裁减的情况下
And my sources around here tell me that, with all the budget cutbacks,
今年你们能用作窃听的
the only wiretap you all have had up this year
只有流浪汉谋杀案名目下的资源
has been on the homeless killer thing.
你们挪作他用是违法的
Whatever else you're running is illegal.
情报来源?
Sources?
监听应该是保密的 Maury
Title threes are supposed to be secret.
你是说你在法院里有情报来源吗
Are you saying you have a source of information inside the courthouse?
只是个比喻的说法
It's a figure of speech.
我要说的是你的案子里有猫腻
What I'm saying is that there's shit in the blood of your case,
如果你就这么起诉
and, if you wait until this goes past indictments,
我会用它大开杀戒的
I'm gonna run wild with it.
我们该谈谈
We should talk.
庭外谈
Out of court.
操蛋
Fuck me.
够了吗 你掌握的够了吗
Is it enough? Do you have enough?
肯定够了 必须够了
It has to be. It should be.
你看了这些Robert的发现
You can't look at everything that Robert found,
不可能看不出那臭小子是什么人
at the pattern, and not see what this fucking guy's about.
你知 我知
You know that. I know that.
你为什么不这么想
What, you don't think so?
我觉得 如果你这么干了
I think that if you do this,
那些狗娘养的会整死你
these son of a bitches will do you.
进来
Come.
打扰了 又发生了一起流浪汉谋杀案
Sorry. There's been another homeless murder.
南巴尔的摩
South Baltimore.
当心点 Gus
Careful, Gus.
我保不了你
I can't protect you.
-不可能 -死了有一会儿了
- No fucking way. - Dead for a while.
照我看...Jimmy 丝带不是红色的
And I can assume, Jimmy, from the fact that the ribbon ain't red
Marlo被捕 你也不需要再来一具尸体了
and the fact that you don't need another body because Marlo is locked up...
- 这跟我无关 - 太好了 我们排除了一个疑犯
- I got nothing to do with this. - Wonderful. We've eliminated one suspect.
看见你都干了什么好事了吗
You see what you started here?
老大们会把这案子交给你的 肯定的
The bosses are gonna toss it back to you. No doubt.
- 老大们知道是我们造假了 - 什么
- The bosses know it's bullshit. - What?
- Daniels知道了 Pearlman也知道 - 你他妈怎么...
- Daniels knows. Pearlman, too. - How the fuck you?
- 多久了... - 让我们私下聊会儿?
- How much longer does this... - Can you give us a minute?
你搞的鬼弄得天翻地覆
You turning the world upside down with your bullshit.
- 怎么你还没进号子 - 不知道
- How are you not in jail? - I don't know.
谎撒得太大了 大到人们可以接受
The lie's so big, people can live with it.
娘的 Jimmy 我早说过 我他妈早告诉过你会到今天这步田地
Jesus fucking Christ, Jimmy. I told you. I fuckin' told you it was going to come to this.
你在玩火 对吗 会把我们都烧死...
You played with fire, didn't you? And now we're all getting burned...
...南巴尔的摩实况报道 警方在这里又发现了一具
...reporting live from South Baltimore, where police have found the body
疑似流浪汉的尸体
of what appears to be another homeless man.
被杀害并抛弃在一个空屋停车场...
This one killed and left in a vacant lot...
不久之前
...short while ago have refused so far...
有人没懂我的话吗
Did somebody not get the message?
至少告诉我 McNulty 那些人不是你杀的吧
You're not killing them yourself, McNulty, at least assure me of that.
那个你弄失踪的人呢
And the one you disappeared?
他没事 就我所知
He's OK, last I checked.
很好 这是个好的开始
Good. That's a start, I guess.
- 我以为你已经收到消息了呢 - 模仿犯
- I thought you got a message. - Copycat.
这事不是我干的
I got nothing on this one.
老天
Jesus.
你怎么办到的 你怎么骗过法医的
How did you do it? How did you get 'em by the medical examiner?
有些是真的 我只是给他们绑上丝带
Some were real and I just linked 'em with the ribbons.
有些我做出些像被勒死的痕迹
Some I juked as strangle jobs.
- 我现在知道事情大条了... - 去你的现在知道了
- If it matters, I know now... - Fuck what you know now.
都是为了钱 McNulty? 没加班费你就活不了了?
This was all for money, McNulty? You couldn't live without the O. T?
是为了Stanfield案
The Stanfield case. It was that.
我知道钱的去向 但你也得付出代价
I know where it went, but you got paid, too.
你和Freamon 也许还有其他一票人
You and Freamon and maybe a dozen other guys.
不是因为钱
It wasn't about the money.
等我们把事情摆平了
Down the road, when we settle on this,
放心 我们会摆平的
and we will settle on this,
你们别再想有哪怕一个小时的加班费
I don't expect any of you will ever see another hour of O.T. Again.
我也不指望你们能做好警务工作了
I don't expect any of you will be doing police work ever again.
你们之所以还没被送到大陪审团面前
And the only reason this isn't before a grand jury right now
仅仅是因为市长无法容忍此事曝光
is because our mayor can't live with that.
没错 市长知道你的大名了
Oh, yeah. The Mayor knows your name.
这是你最后一个案子了 办好它
So this is your last case. Work it.
如果你有你想象的一半那么好
If you're half the detective you think you are,
就快点把这案子结了 让我们摆脱困境
you'll put this one down fast and take us all off the hook.
拖得越久
The longer this goes on,
你死得越难看
the worse the payback's gonna be.
他究竟知道多少
But what does he really know?
他现在知道的 还不到证据开释时将要知道的一半
What he knows now isn't half of what he'll learn when we get to discovery.
他们弄不出一个可靠的线人
They won't be able to produce a credible source of information.
不是登记在案的线人就没必要上庭 - 线人只有...
They don't have to if it's not a registered C. I. A source is only...
如果他激起法官的疑虑
If he can raise doubts in a judge's mind,
我们可能要被迫亮出我们的情报来源
we could be compelled to reveal our source.
那时 我们就得承认窃听
At that point, we're giving up the wiretap.
而他会拿到电话公司的文件
And he gets the paperwork from the phone company.
上面有Stanfield的号码
Which has Stanfield's number on it.
老天
God.
我们只能进行司法交易
The only thing we can do is barter.
那就交易吧 事情不能在法庭公开
Then barter. This can't go to court.
我们还有些手段
We do have some leverage.
什么
What?
这么说吧 Levy先生还有些自己的问题
Let's just say Mr. Levy has problems of his own to deal with.
搞定这事...
Make this go away...
市长不会忘记你们的贡献的
and the Mayor will not forget that you did so.
我也不会
Nor will I.
Jimmy 别坐着 过来帮忙
Jimmy, ass up an' help us with this.
臭死了
Shit is funky.
- 应该拿到审讯室里的 - 口袋里的东西在哪
- We should take this into the box. - Where's the pocket contents?
那个报道的绑架存疑...
We have questions about the reported kidnapping...
- 那两袋 - 是的 女士
- Those two bags there. - Yes, ma'am.
那该是报纸的问题
Well, that would seem to be the newspaper's problem.
要是我再接到一通灰色货车的报警电话
I get another fucking call about a gray van,
我非把报纸大楼夷为平地不可
I'm burning that fucking newspaper building to the ground.
怎么
What?
几天前那个流浪汉口袋里有什么
Your homeless guy from days ago, what was in his pockets?
- 狗屎 - 名片你还有吗
- Bullshit. - You got business cards?
但名片上的人都有不在场证明
Yeah, but every card has an alibi.
- 我看看 - 不是已经看过了吗
- Let me see. - I thought we were done with this.
你要干嘛
So, where you going with this?
- 案子破了 - 你哪有那么犀利
- I think it's down. - Motherfucker, you ain't that good.
McNulty 怎么回事
McNulty, what's up with this?
没事吧 Gus?
You OK, Gus?
没事
Yeah, I'm good.
干嘛
What?
Alma 什么事
Alma, what's up?
- 空白的 - 什么空白的
- It's empty. - What's empty?
他向你挥的便签纸 说上面记满了东西
The pad he waved at you, saying it was all filled with notes.
是空白的 每一页都是
It's empty. Every page.
谢谢
Thanks.
发生什么事了
What the fuck is that about?
Alma  电视里警方在扫荡
Alma, TV has police on a sweep of the homeless
Hanover街的流浪汉
under Hanover street.
我有话直说了
I'll get right to the point.
请吧
Please do.
- Maury 嗨 - 嗨
- Maury,hey. -Hey.
-你替Stanfield辩护是吧  他是你委托人? -对 他和他手下
- You have Stanfield, right? He's your client? - Yeah, him and his people.
我手头有些资料 刚从大陪审团那儿拿到
I have some stuff, straight from the grand jury
你会想尽快看到
that you're gonna wanna see sooner rather than later.
- 是监听的案子吗 - 你会喜欢的 我保证
- Is this a title three case? - You'll find it interesting, I promise.
- 好吧 什么时候见面 - 明天 下班后 老价钱 对吧
- All right. When can you meet? - Tomorrow, after work. Same money, right?
- 嗯 老价钱 - 很好
- Yeah, the money's the same. - Good.
我们可以明天把Gary DiPasquale 交给大陪审团
We can grand jury Gary diPasquale tomorrow,
附上单方同意的窃听材料
along with that one-party consent call.
或者...
Or...
我们做笔交易
here's the deal.
不经庭审
No court trials.
Partlow承认所有空屋谋杀案 终身监禁 不得假释
Partlow pleads to all of the bodies in the vacants and takes life, no parole.
我们还想找到第二名凶手 但Pearson已经挂了
We'd want the second shooter, too, but Pearson's beyond that now.
Metcalf和Wagstaff认故意持有毒品
Metcalf and Wagstaff plead to possession with intent.
Stanfield认同谋罪 判10年
Stanfield takes ten years on conspiracy.
你在勒索一个法庭工作人员
You're blackmailing an officer of the court.
你进来谈条件那一刻
The moment you came in here and offered that quid pro quo,
你就犯了妨碍司法公正的罪
you were guilty of obstruction of justice.
没错
You're right.
我可能会被判6到8年
I could get six to eight years.
而你因贿赂州检查官员 与破坏大陪审团保密条例
And for bribery of a state's attorney and the violation of grand jury secrecy,
会被判10到12年
you could see ten to twelve.
我会比你早几年出狱
I'll be out a couple years before you.
你回家第一轮酒就由我请你吧
You come home, first round's on me, I guess.
这么说你宁可放过我 也不想让案子在法庭上公开咯?
So you'll let me walk to keep this case out of open court?
那一定是黑幕重重啊
That file must be dirty as hell.
没了手机作为证据
The conspiracy charge on Stanfield falls without the cellphones
你我都知道如果深入挖掘一番
and you and I both know that if someone does some digging,
非法窃听就会浮出水面 那电话证据也没用了
they're gonna find an illegal wiretap and you're gonna lose the phones.
Everhart对州政府
Everhart, 274,
Ceccolini对联邦政府
Maryland 459, Ceccolini, 435,
US, 268.
说谎的警察毁不掉一个案子
Lying cops don't automatically kill a case.
但是上诉有很大风险
But that's a lot of risk on appeal.
况且还有那么多见不得人的事
And a lot of dirt for your office to show.
不 你们怕见光
No. You're scared of the light.
Partlow可以赌一把 只应付那起合法途径结案的谋杀起诉
Partlow takes his chances on the legit murder charge only.
同谋罪没戏 Stanfield和其他人也能脱身
The conspiracy count goes and Stanfield and the rest walk.
Stanfield可以无罪
Stanfield walks
不过案子只是暂时压下 并不撤销
but the case goes on the stet docket, not dismissed outright.
我可以告诉你 市里有人
And, although I can tell you there are people in this city
在这个关键时刻不能忍受丑闻
who can't tolerate a scandal at this particular moment,
不过11月之后就不同了
that dynamic changes after November.
-竞选 -11月之后
- The elections. - After November,
谁也不在乎让事情见光
no one is going to care as much about showing dirt.
Carcetti要是赢了 他就在安纳波利斯了
If Carcetti wins, he's in Annapolis.
如果他输了 也还是现任市长 背一两件骂名也没什么
If he loses, he's an incumbent mayor who can take a hit or two.
转告Stanfield先生 这是他唯一的机会
So tell Mr. Stanfield that this is his only window.
Partlow承认所有的谋杀罪名
Partlow pleads to all the murders
两个副手承认贩毒
and both lieutenants plead to the drugs.
然后Stanfield退休
Then Stanfield retires.
他完了
He's done.
再让我们发现他出来混
We even get the scent of him on the street ever again,
我们就重启案件 寻求庭审
this case comes off stet and goes to trial.
如果对付他要把几个警察扔进监狱 那就这样好了
And if we have to put a few cops in jail right behind him, so be it.
我们会拿出证据搏一把
We'll bring the evidence and take a hit.
要么你的委托人现在脱身...
Your client walks away now...
要不你们两个永世不得翻身
or the both of you don't walk at all.
起来
Let's go. Get up.
那是我的
That's mine.
我知道
It's yours. I know.
你有名片吗
Do you have a card?
这不是名片
That's not a card.
我们见过 记得吗
We met before, d'you remember?
骗子
Liar.
黑人骗子
Black liar.
你为什么要杀你朋友
Why'd you kill your friend?
他酗酒
He drinks.
整天喝个不停
He's always drinking.
那还在他手腕上绑了条丝带
But you put a ribbon around his wrist.
就像其他人一样
Like the others.
- 对 - 你从电视上看到的吗
- Yeah. - Did you see that on television?
手腕上的丝带
The ribbon on the wrist?
还是从别人那儿听来的
Did you hear about that from other people?
你为什么要绑丝带
Why'd you do the thing with the ribbon?
没人明白
Nobody understands.
你们都不会明白
You don't understand.
我总是在行动之前...
I always know what I'm going to do...
就知道自己该干什么了
before I do it. OK?
我总是知道自己要做什么
I always know what I'm going to do.
你还杀过其他人吗 他们都是你杀的吗
Did you kill the others? Did you kill all of them?
都是我杀的
Every one of them.
我杀他们是因为我知道我要杀他们
I did it because I knew I was going to do it.
我杀了上百万人
I've killed millions.
他们也杀了我
OK? And they all killed me.
所以所有的案子都是你犯下的?
So you did all the murders?
你是个懦夫
You're a coward.
我看得出来
I can tell.
你有名片吗
Do you have a card?
Jimmy 那个记者来了 等着认照片
Jimmy, reporter's in there waiting for a photo array.
什么 Jay 他报假案
What? Jay, he's bullshit.
我知道 但报纸搞出了很大动静
I know he is but the newspaper made such a fuss,
警长让我们敷衍他一下
the major wants us to jerk him off, just to say we did.
嗨 警探
Hey, detective.
没什么灰色货车
No gray van either.
- 什么 - 他没有灰色货车
- What? - He doesn't have a gray van.
没有灰色货车 他也没给你打电话 不是吗
No gray van. And he didn't call you on the phone either, did he?
他没给你打过第一个电话 也没打过第二个 第二个是我打的
He didn't call you the first time and he didn't call you the second. I did that.
乃让偶在老头子面前蒙羞...(此处模仿巴尔的摩口音)
Yew mortify me in fronta my fatha...
还有你收到的那些照片
And those pictures you got.
是我拍的
I took those.
那个失踪者 是我二表弟
And the missing guy? He's my second cousin.
我们给了他一笔钱 送他去大西洋城玩
We sent him up to Atlantic City with a roll of quarters.
你知道我为什么要告诉你吗
And you know why I can tell you all this?
因为你这个满嘴谎言的混球
Because, you lying motherfucker,
跟我是一丘之貉
you're as full of shit as I am.
而你还得把戏继续演下去 对吧
And you've got to live with it and play it out for as long as it goes. Right?
困在同一个谎言里
Trapped in the same lie.
我们唯一的区别是 我知道自己为什么这么做
Only difference is I know why I did it.
我才不在乎你最终会怎样
But fuck if I can figure out what it gets you in the end.
但我可不是你同类
But hey, I ain't part of your tribe.
- 你开玩笑的吧 你不能... - 对
- You're not serious? You can't... - No.
对 我他妈是个笑话
No, I'm a fucking joke.
你也是
And so are you.
滚你妈的蛋
Now get the fuck out of here.
你可以无罪
You walk.
Chris要承担所有谋杀 终身监禁不得假释
Chris eats the murders, every last one, takes life without parole.
- 不能假释? - 不能
- No parole? - No shot.
他们在某具尸体上发现了他的DNA
They've got him cold on the one with the D.N.A.
没问题吗 Chris忠于你吗
Can you sell that? Is Chris loyal?
嗯
Yeah.
只要我能照顾好他家人
As long as I take care of his people.
Cheese和Monk因贩毒面临二十年刑期
Cheese and Monk are looking at up to twenty for the drugs.
但不会有财产调查 你的钱还是你的
But there's gonna be no assets investigation and you come home with all your money.
他们为什么放过我
Why they letting me walk?
他们也不想 但案子有猫腻
They don't wanna but there's some shit in their case
他们宁可不在庭上展示出来
and they'd rather not show it in court.
事实上 如果你还继续贩毒
But here's the rub. If you stay in the game,
他们会搏一把的 肯定会
they will. They definitely will.
现在 选举在即
Right now, with an election going on,
他们愿意放你一马
they're willing to give you a bye.
但11月之后 如果他们发现你还在贩毒
But after November, if they even think you're still a player,
他们会旧案重提
they can take this case down off the shelf
调查过程中的猫腻也不足以让你脱身
and the shit in the case might not be enough to keep you free.
懂了吗
You understand?
金盆洗手
Give up the crown.
这就是条件 孩子
Well, that's the deal, kiddo.
没哪个律师能争取到更好的条件了
There's not a lawyer who could get better for you.
怎么样 老板
How'd that go, boss?
小子 你真是我的财神
Kiddo, you are a gold mine to me. You know that?
- 你把我的律所推上了新的高度 - 我?
You've taken this law firm to a whole new level.
要不是你提醒了我有非法的窃听 我麻烦就大了
- Me? - You don't tip me to that bad wiretap,
如果Marlo接受交易
I've got all kinds of trouble. But now, if Marlo takes the deal,
他面临贩售价值 数百万美元毒品的指控还能脱身
he's gonna get a walk after being charged in a multimillion-dollar drug seizure.
这不常见啊
That doesn't happen very often
一旦做到了 辩护律师的名字和电话
and, when it does happen, the name and number
就会跑到每个可敬的毒贩的口袋里
of the defense attorney goes in the front pocket of every respectable drug trafficker.
你真是个天才 太有贡献了
You're a genius for what you brought me on this.
我只是做我该做的 不是吗
I'm just doing what I do, right?
想知道什么 就去问
You need to know something, all you gotta do is ask.
侦探不就是干这个的嘛
That's what a detective is, right?
给 今晚过来吃个晚饭吧
Here. You should come over for dinner tonight.
- Yvette炖了胸肉 - 去你家?
- Yvette's making brisket. - Your house?
我们是一家人了
You're mishpocha now.
你说是就是吧
If you say so.
结了
It's down.
倒没什么上庭的必要 那家伙一看就精神不健全(无犯罪责任)
Not that this thing is ever going to trial. That guy has N.C.R. Written all over him.
无法抗辩 Clifton T. Perkins医院的软垫病房是去定了
Can't argue. A padded room at Clifton T. Perkins is definitely called for.
- 所有案子他都认了? - 没有 长官 只认了最后两件
- He go for all of them? - No, sir. Just the last two.
- 他否认其他的案子? - 他什么都没有否认
- He deny the others? - He ain't exactly denying anything in there.
我们要安什么莫须有的罪名都行
I mean, he'll cop to anything we damn please.
那就回去 让他认罪
Then go back and get it.
什么
Excuse me?
如果他精神不健全 认2件跟认6件有什么区别
If he's N.C.R., what the fuck is the difference if he cops to two or six?
不管怎样 他们都会绑着他胳膊 喂他绿色的果冻
Either way, they tie his arms and feed him green Jell-o.
长官 他只犯了最后两件案子
Sir, he did the last two.
混账
Motherfucker.
你就快被起诉了 还要跟我争?
You are a cunt hair away from indictment and you see fit to argue with me?
我知道我做错了
I did what I did. I know.
现在我负责的是两件新的谋杀案
And now I'm standing responsible for two fresh murders.
我知道我做了什么
I know what I've done here.
但我绝不同意这么做
But I'm not doing this.
都结束了
This is over
市民们可以安心了 由于警方辛勤的工作
and all of our citizens can rest soundly in the knowledge that the man responsible
流浪汉谋杀案的凶手已被逮捕
has been apprehended by the diligent efforts of investigators.
市长先生 他是以最后两桩谋杀案 还是所有谋杀案被起诉?
Mr. Mayor, is he being charged with all of the murders
据我所知...
- or just two? - It is my understanding that...
我们起诉的是最后两桩谋杀
We are charging the last two incidents
但他涉嫌实施了所有的案子
but it is my understanding that he is suspected in all of the crimes.
我们正在等待DNA检测结果
We're waiting for D.N.A. Test results.
有迹象表明他精神不健全
Indications are that he may be mentally incapacitated
因此额外的检控是多余的
and therefore additional prosecutions would prove redundant.
同时我要表扬Daniels副局长
I would also like to credit Deputy Commissioner for Operations Daniels
不仅漂亮地解决了这几起案子
with not only bringing these cases to their proper conclusion
还解决了去年的空屋谋杀案
but also for solving last year's slayings in the vacant rowhouses.
他工作出色
He has given us such excellent work
我认为是时候向各位宣布
that I think that now is as good a time as any to announce
我们会向市议会推荐他
that we will be sending the deputy's name forward
接任巴尔的摩市警察局长
to the city council for confirmation as Baltimore Police Commissioner.
同时非常感谢代理警察局长Rawls
Acting commissioner Rawls, to whom I am also extremely grateful,
他将在市政厅暂时担任顾问性的工作 等待新的任命
will serve in an advisory capacity pending new responsibilities at City Hall.
Scott
你该跟Alma合作撰写逮捕行动的新闻
You should be working the main bar on the arrest with Alma.
我...
I...
这篇报道要你署名
We're going to want your byline in this coverage.
我不太舒服 胃有点...
Yeah, I don't feel so well. My stomach...
我该回家了
I think I gotta go home.
抱歉
Sorry.
得以避开流浪汉谋杀案的大风波
Having ducked the bullet on that homeless mess,
我和市长都很感激你审慎的处理
I want you to know that the Mayor and I both appreciate your discretion.
但总体犯罪率的问题
But right now we can't take our eyes off the ball
仍然不可忽视
when it comes to crime overall.
看着你上周各区的犯罪报告调查
Looking at your weekly U.C.R. S from the districts,
我看不出犯罪率
I am not seeing the kind of decline that's going to measure out
能在这季度下降百分之十
to a ten per cent drop in the quarter.
- 它们是真实的 - 什么
- They're clean. - Excuse me?
统计是真实的
The stats are clean.
今后也一定要是真实的
They're gonna stay clean.
要么我们完善警局 让犯罪率下降
Either we fix this Police Department and the crime goes down
要么撒手不管 犯罪率飙升
or we don't and the crime stays up.
局长 我们只是需要你
Commissioner, we're talking about a little help
在接下来两个季度里帮点小忙 如此而已
in the next couple quarters. That's all.
不行
No. I can't.
流浪汉的事你能保持沉默 这个就让你坐不住了? 你搞...
You're quiet on the homeless fiasco but this makes you squeal?
告诉市长 我会给他真实的数据
Tell the Mayor his stats will be clean
选举前也好 选举后也罢
before the election, after the election.
也对 他们没法炒了你
You're right. They can't fire you.
那是市政厅搬起石头砸自己的脚
Not without it bouncing back on City Hall.
如果你不介意被埋没在 一个不见天日的单位里
If you don't mind being buried in some backroom unit,
你想待多久就待多久
you can stay for as long as you can stand it.
直到你退休
Or until you get the pension.
但同时 我不会再让你做警务工作
But, at the same time, I can't let you do police work.
不是所有的事都能上法庭的
Not anything that's going to find its way into a courtroom.
我也不会那么做
I won't do that.
对你们俩都是
For both of you,
到此为止了
that's over.
这么说Marlo逍遥法外了
So Marlo walks.
或者你进监狱
Or you go to jail.
而且你也拿Levy没办法?
And you couldn't do any better with Levy?
我是说 考虑到那些钱的交易...
I mean, giving up the money...
我尽力了
I got what I could.
你决定不依法行动那一刻 Lester
You lost the money trail, Lester,
资金链的调查就已经完了
when you decided to start colouring outside the lines.
这不是我的错
This isn't on me.
你出售个毛啊
What the fuck you mean you selling?
- 我要出售跟卖家的联系 - 多少钱
- I'm sellin' the connect. - How much, yo?
- 1千万 - 靠
- Ten million. - Goddamn.
如果你们不止一个愿出这个价 那就价高者得
Or a high bid if I hear ten from more than one of y'all.
如果你们认为不值 那我就不卖了
Y'all think it ain't worth that, I stick that shit back in my pocket
你们大可以回去卖纽约的次货
and y'all can go back to runnin' that stepped-on New York shit.
不介意的话我问问 为什么要卖
You don't mind me askin', why you sellin'?
就算在号子里  你也还是可以分一杯羹的
I mean, even from inside here, you can take a slice for just layin' in the cut, nigger.
我不会在这待很久的
Ain't gonna be in here long.
他们对我的起诉已经没戏了
Case they got against me already fallin' apart.
但事实上
But the truth is,
我也得金盆洗手了
I'm done with this gangsta shit.
我风光过了
I've been there, done that.
你除了混帮派还能干别的?
You somethin' else other than a gangsta?
生意人 没错 大个子
Businessman. Yeah, Tall Man,
我也没那脑子
I can't get that shit wrapped around my head neither.
总之 你们要是付不起 可以凑钱
Anyway, y'all can't get my price up, maybe y'all pool your money.
但我出去后
But supply only gonna deal with y'all
才会跟你们交易
after I make the intro.
然后我就退出
Then I'm out.
你有麻烦了 我还以为Daniels对你俯首帖耳呢
You've got a problem. I thought Daniels was your boy.
犯罪率不降我们都有麻烦
We both got a problem if crime doesn't drop.
Carcetti当不了州长 你也当不了市长
Carcetti loses the statehouse and you aren't mayor.
就算他赢了 Nerese  有个不听话的局长
And even if he wins, Nerese, you're stuck
你也是绑手绑脚的
with a Police Commissioner that won't work with you.
我不会被任何人束缚
I'm not stuck with anything.
Daniels要么恢复理智 要么他就玩完
Daniels either comes around or he's done.
我们刚选定了他  不能马上反悔 他知道这点
We just anointed him. We can't go back on that now. He knows it.
他要么搞清楚自己的立场 要么辞职
Either he learns his place or he'll be offering to resign.
不是只有你才会玩这个游戏的
You ain't the only one knows how to play this game.
该怎么形容这个难搞的家伙呢
What to say about this piece of work?
如果我没找到合适的话 那我真该死
Fucked if I don't find myself without the right words.
我作为一个跟你们一样天生的金嗓子
Me, as gifted a golden throat as any of you cocksuckers
多年来离经叛道
being loosed from religion, are ever likely to hear.
我该如何总结这个可贵的往者
What can I say about the dearly departed?
- 真的... - 他英年早逝
- I mean, really... - He died young.
- 死太早了 - 还不到40
- Too young. - Not even 40 years old.
虽然就算活着 他的鸡巴也134岁了
Though, had it lived, his dick woulda been 134.
闭嘴 灵感来了
Shut up. It's coming to me.
他是害群之马
He was the black sheep,
永世被放逐者
the permanent pariah.
他不向大人们摇尾乞怜 也从未被怜悯
He asked no quarter of the bosses and none was given.
不接受教训
He learned no lessons,
一错再错
he acknowledged no mistakes.
他是个倔强的爱尔兰佬 徘徊于东北郊区之外
He was as stubborn a Mick as ever stumbled
只为获得一枚警徽
out of the Northeast parishes to take a patrolman's shield.
他藐视权威
He brooked no authority.
他随兴所至 口无遮拦
He did what he wanted to do and he said what he wanted to say
最终 他能给你一个真相
and, in the end, he gave you the clearances.
他是个天生的警察 没错
- He's natural police. - Yes, he was.
我一般不这么说别人 即便他们躺在这上面
I don't say that about many people, even when they're here on the felt.
除非是事实 我不会轻易给人这个名号
I don't give that one up unless it happens to be true.
天生的警察
Natural poh-leece.
但老天啊 他个屁眼儿的
But Christ, what an asshole.
我说的可不是我们都有的那个平凡的洞洞
And I'm not talkin' about the ordinary, gaping orifice that all of us possess.
我说的是一个包罗万象 让人劳心劳力
I mean an all-encompassing, all-consuming,
跟他人性的其他方面不成比例的深坑
out of proportion to every other facet of his humanity chasm.
其深远 恕我引用莎士比亚
From whose borne, if I may quote Shakespeare,
不曾有一个旅人回来 (引自哈姆雷特)
no traveler has ever returned.
- 我他妈干什么了 - 闭上你鸟嘴
- The fuck did I do? - Shut the fuck up.
你是个死人
You're dead to us now.
这不是他一起犯罪的搭档嘛
Here's his partner in crime.
温柔点 温柔点
Now, now. Be gentle. Be gentle.
我现在是个平头百姓了 温柔点
I'm a civilian now. Be gentle.
你辞呈递上去了?
Your papers went in?
- 嗯 中午交的 32年了 - 又4个月
- Yeah, this afternoon. 32 years. - And four months.
你们给他送的好终啊
Y'all did a fine job with him, you did.
他比我记忆中要年轻10岁
He look to be about ten years younger than I remember.
起来了 这里可躺不下两个人
Well, c'mon, there's enough room for both of you to be laid out.
一次一个
One at a time.
都追悼会了 你还围着人家啊
You don't crowd a man at his own wake.
来嘛 Lester 来抱抱嘛
Come on, Lester. Come and snuggle.
别声张 Jimmy 我带了Shardene来呢
Keep our secrets, Jimmy. I got Shardene with me tonight.
如果各位大量无视这次不幸的同性恋丑闻
If you gentlemen will spare us this unfortunate homoerotic lapse,
我想把我的丧礼发言说完
I will conclude my elegiac remarks.
说啊 你个多嘴的烂人
Then do it, you gabby motherfucker.
让我说完
To conclude. To conclude,
总之 他跟我们共事了13年
I say he gave us 13 years on the line.
还不够拿退休金的 但足够我们了解到...
Not enough for a pension but enough for us to know that he was...
他妈的放歌吧
Put the fucking song on.
...尽管他有微不足道的爱尔兰血统
...despite his negligible Irish ancestry,
他人格上颇多缺陷
his defects of personality,
还有他时有时无的清醒和卫生
and his inconstant sobriety and hygiene,
他是个真正的凶案警探
a true murder police.
Jimmy
我真心的
I say this seriously.
如果我死在巴尔的摩的某个街角
If I was laying there dead on some Baltimore street corner,
我希望是你来调查我的案子
I'd want it to be you standing over me, catching the case.
放屁
Bullshit.
因为 哥们 你状态好时 是最棒的
Because, brother, when you were good, you were the best we had.
靠 如果你死在某个街角 很可能就是Jimmy下的手
Shit, if you was lying there dead on some corner, it was probably Jimmy that done ya.
去你的 如果是你接这案子
Fuck you! If you caught the case,
你怕是会在我耳边撒尿了
you'd be standing there pissing in my ear.
Nerese Campbell怎么弄来的
How did Nerese Campbell get it?
你觉得我会问吗 你觉得这重要吗
You think I asked? Do you think it even matters?
她交给我 是因为她认为你会听我的
She gave it to me because she thought you'd listen to me.
这么说他们现在想让我走人了
So now they want me to go.
她的意思是 她想让你留下
The way she expressed it is that she wanted you to stay
如果你能恢复理智的话
if you could come to your senses.
恢复理智
Come to my senses.
她想让我帮Carcetti伪造数据 这个季度和下个...
She wants me to juke the stats for Carcetti, this quarter and the next,
隐瞒犯罪 让他当选州长
hide the crime, get him elected as governor
让她坐上市长的位子
and make her the Mayor.
照办啊 Burrell之前就是这么干的
So do it. Burrell juked them before you.
他之前的Warren Frasier也是
Warren Frasier before him.
你走人的话 Rawls或别的什么人 也会这么干 那又如何
And, after you're gone, Rawls or whoever will juke them. So what?
必要时 我也能自欺欺人
I'll swallow a lie when I have to.
最近我就接受了好几个弥天大谎
I've swallowed a few big ones lately.
但这个数据游戏...这个谎言正在毁灭这个警局
But the stat games, that lie, it's what ruined this department.
糊上金纸就当是黄金了
Shining up shit and calling it gold,
警长就成了总警监  市长就成了州长
so majors become colonels and mayors become governors.
假装做着警务工作 却教着后继者如何
Pretending to do police work while one generation fucking trains the next
不做警务工作 还有...
how not to do the job. And then...
我双眼直视Carcetti
I looked Carcetti in the eye.
握着他的手 问他是不是来真的
I shook his hand. I asked him if he was for real.
这不是我能容忍的谎言
This is the lie I can't live with.
如果我默许了 就得对Nerese俯首帖耳
If I do, then Nerese has me in her pocket whenever she wants me.
我不擅长这个
And I'm no good to anyone like that.
那就离开
Then go.
因为私人原因或健康原因辞职
Withdraw for personal reasons or health reasons.
怎么都好
Whatever.
你有了法学学位 饿不死的
You've got your law degree. You're not gonna starve.
如果你不去职 他们会毁了我们俩
But if you don't go, they'll wreck both of us.
这些还够不上起诉我
There's not enough in here to indict me.
讽刺的是
And the joke of it is,
我这几天来所见所闻 已经足以让他们被起诉了
I've seen enough the last few days to have them indicted.
为什么
For what?
那你利用起来啊 Cedric 或至少拿它来威胁他们
Then use it, Cedric, or at least threaten to.
会有人受到伤害的
People will get hurt.
我在乎的人
People I care about.
那你就完了 这文件里的东西
Then you're done. There's enough in that file
足以让你通不过任命听证会
that you'll never make it through confirmation hearings.
足以在我的职业生涯还没开始前就毁了我
And enough so that my career is dead before it even gets started.
刚极易折 Cedric
The tree that doesn't bend breaks, Cedric.
过分屈服 也是损坏了
Bend too far, you're already broken.
Marlo逍遥法外
Marlo on a walk.
还有钱的线索 Jimmy  她也放弃了
And the money, she gave that away, too.
是啊
Yeah.
我们追踪不了资金链了
We don't get to follow the money.
嘿... 还在想你上哪去了...
Hey, wonderin' where you was.
不知道我该不该来这儿...
I didn't know if I should come out on this here.
为什么不行
Why the fuck not?
是我向Daniels告的密
Was me who told Daniels.
我不想背后捅你们一刀 但是...
I didn't want to do it behind your back but...
事情必须有个了结
it had to be done.
总之 跟你们共事真的很棒
Anyway, it was great being on the job with y'all.
我就想这么说
I just wanted to say that too, I guess.
那现在怎样
So what?
你再不跟我喝酒了?
You ain't gonna drink with me?
如果你叫上我的话 我就来
I am if you want.
警探
Detective,
如果你认为应该来
if you think it needed doing...
那就是应该的
I guess it did.
你来不
You coming?
Milton有60万
Milton came with 600.
Little Glen出30万
And Little Glen is in for three.
我有50万
I got five from me
还从中国佬那儿拉了50万
and I got five from Chinaman to cover.
还差90万 - 我出吧 小意思
- We still short 900. - I can go that. No thing.
-什么?你哪来那么多钱
What? Motherfucker, where you get that kind of scratch?
你不觉得Cheese我很会玩这游戏吗
You don't think Cheese know this here game?
我们可是在巴尔的摩卖毒品 黑鬼
We sellin' dope an' coke in Baltimore, nigger,
赚不到那么多钱才该惭愧吧
any of y'all ain't got that kind of money need be ashamed.
你付的还是超过了你的份额
You still puttin' up more than your share with that.
我的看法是 我们有赚不赔...
The way I look at it, we all gonna be more than paid
一旦我们取得接头方式 所以...
once we own the connect, so...
你叔叔掌舵时 我们生意可好了
Shit, nigger, we was good when your uncle had it.
然后却要忍受Marlo...
You had to go ahead and put up with Marlo.
看见没 看见没
See that? See now,
这就是错误的看法
that's just the wrong way to look at it
Joe风光过 被Omar了结了
'cause Joe had his time and Omar put an end to that.
然后是Marlo的时代 一闪即逝
Then Marlo had his time, short as it was,
被警方终结了
and the police put an end to that.
混球 现在是我们的时代了
And now, motherfucker, it's our time.
我和你们的时代
Mines and yours.
但你不想着闭上嘴凑钱
But instead of just shutting up and kicking in,
只是站在那回忆往昔
you gonna stand there cryin' that back-in-the-day shit.
- Cheese... - 昨日不复返了 老鬼
There ain't no back in the day, nigger.
没什么好怀旧的
Ain't no nostalgia to this shit here.
这里只有街道和游戏
There's just the street and the game
- 和发生在当下的一切
and what happen here today.
你说得对
You right.
当我叔叔掌舵时 我跟着叔叔
When it was my uncle, I was with my uncle.
轮到Marlo了 我也跟着他
When it was Marlo, I was with him.
但现在 混球们...
But now, nigger...
你他妈搞什么
What the fuck did you do that for?
现在我们缺90万了
Now we short the nine.
是为了Joe
That was for Joe.
这个多愁善感的混蛋 还我们损失了一大笔钱
This sentimental motherfucker just cost us money.
回家之路
Alma...
Hey, Alma...
我听说了
I just heard.
Carroll郡分社?他们就这么处罚我?
The Carroll County bureau? That's how they punish me?
干嘛不直接把我发配到宾夕法尼亚
Why not just send my ass all the way to Pennsylvania?
他们怎么跟你说的
What'd they tell you?
说我工作出色 这跟发生的什么事都无关
That I did an excellent job, that this had nothing to do with anything
只是想增强郡分社的实力
but trying to make the county bureaus stronger.
Alma 记事本的事我没说 我隐瞒了那事
Alma, I didn't tell them about the notepad. I left that part out.
我跟他们说了 我听说你有麻烦了 就去见了Whiting
I told them. When I heard you were in trouble, I went to Whiting,
告诉他我认为你对Scott的看法是对的 我告诉了他们记事本的事
told him I thought you were right about Scott. I told him about the notepad.
所有的都是他编的吗
Did he make all of it up?
-凶手的来电? 照片? -有些是 不全是
- The calls from the killer? The pictures? - Some, not all.
-为什么 -你看看四周
- Why? - Look around.
池塘干涸了
The pond is shrinking.
鱼儿们都很紧张
The fish are nervous.
弄些报道获个奖...
Get some profile, win a prize,
也许就能跳到个大点的池塘里
maybe find a bigger pond somewhere.
Whiting Klebanow Templeton...
Whiting, Klebanow, Templeton...
他们拿下一两个普利策奖 就能出名 离开这里
They snatch a Pulitzer or two and they are up and gone from this place.
对他们来说 这才是最重要的
For them, that's what this is all about.
而我则太单纯了
Me? I'm too fucking simpleminded for that.
我只想每天看见些新鲜事...
I just wanted to see something new every day
并把它写下来
and write a story with it.
Alma 你很快会从Carroll脱颖而出的 看着吧
Alma, you'll write your way outta Carroll in no time, watch.
就跟你从编辑中脱颖而出一样快?
About as fast as you edit your way off the copy desk?
当我回顾过去挥霍的生命 我越来越确信 报道新闻比什么都有意思 那是国王的生活 H. L. Mencklen
祝贺你 Goette警司
Congratulations, Sergeant Goette.
相信你在东区会有出色表现
I know you'll do well in the Eastern.
很高兴能给你授衔 祝贺你 Carver警督
Glad I got to do this at least. Congratulations, Lieutenant Carver.
谢谢 长官 很遗憾不能在你手底下工作
Thank you, sir. I'm just sorry it won't be you I'm serving under.
已经传开了吗
Word gets around?
今天已经上了巴尔的摩网了
It's on W.B.A.L. Today.
说你因为家庭原因离任...
They said you're leaving for family reasons.
我猜我在某个地方有几个我不知道的孩子吧
I guess I got some kids somewhere I don't even know about.
他们有说派谁来担任代理局长吗
They say on B.A.L. Who they're sending up as acting commissioner? -
还没有决定
Say it ain't so.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
这是我作为巴尔的摩警务人员 的最后一次官方活动
as what may be my last official act as a Baltimore police officer,
请容许我祝贺晋升的警员
allow me to congratulate all of the promoted officers,
以及他们的家人 同事和朋友
their families, their fellow officers and their friends.
你不给我小心点 他们会让你当警长的 到时你就玩完了
You ain't careful, they may make you major, then you'll be truly fucked.
- 干得漂亮 - 谢谢
- Good job. - Thanks.
- 我为你骄傲 - 谢谢
- Proud of you. - Thanks.
看你 不该你操心的时候瞎操心
See now, there you go, giving a fuck when it ain't your turn to give a fuck.
-该Lehman的小队了 -我要加班
- Lehman's squad was up. - I needed the O.T.
那你现在手上就有了件没有目击者的枪击案
Yeah, now you got a shooting with no wits,
没有嫌疑人 没有破案的希望
no suspect and no prayer of it going to black.
像个菜鸟似的电话一来就接 你该感到惭愧
Picking up the phone like a goddamn rookie. Shame on you.
别像个婆娘磨磨唧唧的
Stop squealin' like a bitch.
还有别踩到你身后的弹壳
An' make sure you don't step on that shell casing behind you.
我才不会踩到身后的弹壳 弹壳在路边呢
I ain't gonna kick no shell casings behind me. It's there on the side.
我往回走也不会踢到你没记录的弹壳
I'm gonna step back and kick no shell casing you don't mark with letters and numbers.
我知道 系统里一定有你
I understand. And you gotta be in the system.
他们给你派发了表格 他们跟我说不够好
- They sent you the form. - They told me that wasn't good enough.
他们说要另整一份文档
They said they wanted the other paperwork.
-Belton先生 你要申请补充保证收入? - 你好 女士
- And you applied for S.S. I., Mr. Belton? - Yes, ma'am.
我们进去查查电脑再说吧
Well, let's go inside and look it up on the computer.
你不记得我了?
Hey, you remember me?
我几周前带这人过来 现在想来看看他...
I brought this guy in a few weeks back, just wanted to see how he was.
他几周前走丢了
He wandered out after a couple nights.
抱歉
Sorry.
那...
Where...
-这附近的流浪汉都去哪? -有几个地方 在河那边
- Where do the homeless go around here? - Different places. Down by the river,
仓库区...
over in the warehouse district.
有些地方你去可能不太安全...
Some of the places I don't think it would be safe for you to go.
我是警察 曾经是
I'm police. Well, I used to be.
等等 我给你找张地图
Wait here. I'll see if I can find you a map.
- 谢谢 - 进来吧 Belton先生
- Thanks. - Come on, Mr. Belton.
如果这个警长有点脑子
...and if the major could find his ass with his hand,
他就会知道我们不止能装个拨号记录器
he'd know that we have more than enough to be up on a pen register.
Carver警督跟他说了
Lieutenant Carver told him so.
操蛋的他居然想把案子停了
But fuck if he isn't trying to shut this thing down.
我要说的是 打一两个电话 你就会发现
Alls I'm sayin' is a phone call or two and you're gonna find out
上面某处给了他们些压力 让案件搁置
that they're getting some kinda pressure from somewhere to sit on this thing,
即便我们已经查了这伙人三起谋杀了
even though we've tied three killings to this crew.
局长知道吗
Does the Police Commissioner know?
他?不踢开他前门亮逮捕令 他都不知道什么叫警务工作
Him? He wouldn't know police work if it took down his front door on a warrant.
就...别说是我说的
Just... keep my name out of it.
新Westport就像十年前的Howard大街
New Westport is like Howard Street ten years ago,
只不过土地更便宜
except the land's cheaper
因为滨水而更有发展潜力
and there's more potential for mixed use because of the waterfront location.
你在这儿呢 水景可是无价的
- There you are. - You can't put a price on a water view.
不 你可以
Yes, you can.
当然可以
You definitely can.
Andy 他得见见Tommy 他们要提早离开
Andy, he's gotta meet Tommy and they're leaving early
所以我带他离开一小会
so let me borrow him for a moment.
好的 很高兴见到你 Stanfield先生
Sure, no problem. Nice to meet you, Mr. Stanfield.
你知道你在跟谁说话吗 - 不知道
You know who you were talking to? -No.
Andy Krawczyk
Andy Krawczyk.
八面玲珑 港口的大开发商
Very connected. Very big with development around the harbour.
他是你需要结识的人
He's someone you're gonna wanna know well.
但孩子...
But kid, do not...
别跟他单独共处一室
Do not get in a room with him alone.
相信我 你需要我陪同 否则 他们会让你大出血...
You want me in there with you, believe me, otherwise guys like that will bleed you.
Tommy Flanagan离开前  我想让你见见他...
I want you to meet Tommy Flanagan before he leaves.
行 稍等片刻 我想...
Yeah, gimme a minute. I need to...
- 洗手间? - 嗯
- Bathroom? - Yeah.
大厅右转
Down the hall to the right.
当心 吃多了会发胖的
Hey, watch that stuff. You'll put on weight.
下次 你要确认清楚
But next time, I want you to make sure
你看着这些钱...
that you watch this money...
别... 别乱来
Don't. Don't do it.
把钱交出来
Time to give that up.
你知道我是谁吗
Do you know who I am?
Vinson 以前是Marlo的账房
Name's Vinson. Used to be Marlo's bank,
Marlo不在了 你还在帮其他卖家转移资金
but Marlo ain't around no more and you still moving money for other players,
所以...有些钱该归我
so I'm thinking some of that money need to be mine.
靠...你只是个小鬼
Shit. You just a boy.
那只是你的膝盖
That's just your knee.
那混球开枪打我
That motherfucker shot me.
合作愉快 先生们
Nice doing business, gentlemen.
靠
shit.
不可能 扯淡
No way, that's bullshit.
我听到的不一样 Omar真正的情况是
I heard it different. The real story about Omar
一伙警察伪造出纽约帮派杀了他的样子
is that a bunch of cops made it look like them New York boys killed him.
但其实是他们干的 是他们杀了他
But it was them. They're the ones that really killed him.
听着 混球 我知道是怎么回事
Listen, motherfucker, I know what happened to him.
跟警察无关 也不是纽约帮派干的
Them police had nothing to do with it. No New York boys neither.
Omar拿着把AK 但被包围了
So Omar's got an A.K., right? But he's surrounded.
对方有八九个人 都拿着9毫米手枪
It's like eight, nine motherfuckers up there and they all got nines.
- 但他说"你们以为..." - 你看什么看
- But he like, "You all think you..." - Fuck you lookin' at?
-说你呢 小子 -你们知道我是谁吗
- You, nigger. - Do you know who I am?
你知道我是谁吗
Nigger, you know who I am?
靠
Shit!
Yeah.
- 好... - 这轮我请 怎样
...on me, all right?
哥伦比亚大学 (普利策奖由哥伦比亚大学颁发)
谢谢 谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
今天是民主党的大日子 是马里兰的大日子
This is a great day for Democrats and it's a great day for Maryland.
Zorzi 希望截止期前能到我手上
I hope I get this by e-dot.
行 三分钟 看在上帝的份上 别动不动就发火
OK, three minutes, for Christ's sake. Don't get your panties in a knot.
Valchek局长
Commissioner Valchek.
Valchek来了
Valchek
公诉人女士 先生们...
Madam Prosecutor, gentlemen...
第一件案子 我得要求撤换我
The first case up and I have to recuse myself.
法官阁下 感谢您的关心
Your Honour, I appreciate your concern.
马里兰州警局
恭喜 总警监
Congratulations, Superintendent.
-欢迎加入 - 谢谢 州长
- Welcome aboard. - Thank you, Governor.
-很高兴加入 - 谢谢
- Happy to be aboard. - Thank you.
Larry...
Larry.
我们回家
Let's go home.